Guide to the Central Washington University Relations, Historical Photographs 1891-1978
Central Washington University Archives and Special Collections
Central Washington University Relations, Historical Photographs
1891-1978
Central Washington University, Archives and Special Collections 400 E University Way Ellensburg, WA 98926 (509) 963-1717 http://www.lib.cwu.edu/Archives-Special-Collections archive@cwu.edu
RG027-06-79
Central Washington University Relations
1.5 cubic feet 2 oversize boxes Photographic prints and laminated labels in good condition.
This collection consists of photographic prints and laminated labels for prints depicting Ellensburg, WA, and the campus of Central Washington University (and its predecessors), 1891-1978.
Historical Note
Central Washington University's Advancement Office began as the Office of Public Service in 1938. In 1946 the office was renamed the Publications Office, a name which it retained until 1962 when it became part of the Office of Auxiliary Services. After 1966 it became the College Relations and Financial Aid Office and later, in 1969, the College Information Office. When Central Washington State College became a university in 1977, the office was renamed the University Information Office. In 1979 it was called the University Relations Office, and in 1993 it became the University Advancement Office.
The photographs in this collection include portraits of students and faculty of Washington State Normal School (with names included on the backs of photos); photos of buildings at Washington State Normal School and Central Washington State College; aerial photographs of Ellensburg; and portraits of the school’s presidents from 1891 to 1978.
Central Washington University began as the Washington State Normal School in 1891. In 1937, the school was rechristened the Central Washington College of Education. In 1961, the school became Central Washington State College and, finally, in 1977, Central Washington University.
Arranged chronologically by size
Open to the public for educational research
This collection is indexed under the following headings in the online catalog. Researchers desiring materials about related topics, persons, or places should search the catalog using these headings.
Central Washington University Relations
Ellensburg (Wash.)
Central Washington University--History; Universities and colleges--Washington (State)
Washington (State); Colleges and Universities
Photographic prints
- Benjamin Franklin Barge, Principal, 1891-1894 (Box-folder 1-1)
- P. A. Getz, President, Principal, 1894-1898 (Box-folder 1-2)
- William E. Wilson, Principal/President, 1898-1916 (Box-folder 1-3)
- George H. Black, President, 1916-1930 (Box-folder 1-4)
- Seldon F. Smyser, Acting President, 1930-1931 (Box-folder 1-5)
- Robert E. McConnell, President, 1931-1959 (Box-folder 1-6)
- Perry H. Mitchell, Acting President, 1959-1961 (Box-folder 1-7)
- James E. Brooks, President, 1961-1978 (Box-folder 1-8)
- Donald L. Garrity, President, 1978-1991 (Box-folder 1-9)
- “’Diamond 75’ Anniversary Edition" Newspaper Clipping, Photo of Barge Hall (Box-folder 1-10)
- Group Portrait, Faculty Members, 1892-1898 (Box-folder 1-11)
- Group Portrait, First Graduating Class, 1892 (Box-folder 1-12)
- Old Library Building, Taken by Patrick Crawford, May 1953 (Box-folder 1-13)
- Framed Individual Portraits, Faculty Members, 1904-1905 (Box-folder 1-14)
- Benjamin Franklin Barge, Principal, 1891-1894 (Box-folder 2-1)
- Group Portrait, 25th Anniversary Celebration (reprint), May 25, 1916 (Box-folder 2-2)
- Robert E. McConnell, 1931 (Box-folder 2-3)
- McConnell Auditorium, Taken by I, Spring 1970s (Box-folder 2-4)
- Old Library (Bouillon Hall), 1970s (Box-folder 2-5)
- Bouillon Library, Occupied 1961, 1970s (Box-folder 2-6)
- McConnell Auditorium and Kamola Hall, 1970s (Box-folder 2-7)
- Black Hall, Grupe Center, 1970s (Box-folder 2-8)
- Nicholson Pavilion, 1970s (Box-folder 2-9)
- Grupe Center, Black Hall, 1970s (Box-folder 2-10)
- Student Union Building, 1970s (Box-folder 2-11)
- Barge Hall, 1970s (Box-folder 2-12)
- Dormitories, 1970s (Box-folder 2-13)
- Barge Hall (Box-folder 2-14)
- Ellensburg, 1940s (Box-folder 2-15)
- CWCE United Nations Group, 1957 (Box-folder 2-16)
- Aerial Photo of Campus, 1970s (Box-folder 2-17)
- State Normal School (Box-folder 2-18)
- Laboratory Scene, State Normal School (Box-folder 2-19)
- Group Portrait, Faculty Members, 1892-1893 (Box-folder 2-20)
- Group Portrait, Second Graduating Class, Taken by C.A. Bushnell, 1893 (Box-folder 2-21)
- Group Portrait, Class, 1901 (Box-folder 2-22)
- Group Portrait, Normal School/High School Football Team, 1902 (Box-folder 2-23)
- Group Portrait, Class, 1905 (Box-folder 2-24)
- Group Portrait, Class Members, Early 1900s (Box-folder 2-25)
- Group Portrait, Faculty Members, 1892-1893 (Box-folder 2-26)
- Group Portrait, Class, Taken by C.A. Bushnell, 1894 (Box-folder 2-27)
- Ellensburg Looking South from the Normal School, 1895 (Box-folder 2-28)
- Ellensburg Looking South from the Normal School, 1895 (Box-folder 2-29)
- Group Portrait, Faculty Members, 1895 (Box-folder 2-30)
- Group Portrait, Class, 1897 (Box-folder 2-31)
- Group Portrait, Faculty Members, 1899-1900 (Box-folder 2-32)
- Group Portrait, Class, 1900 (Box-folder 2-33)
- State Normal School, 1900-1901 (Box-folder 2-34)
- Normal School Football Team, 1907-1908 (Box-folder 2-35)
- Group Portrait, 25th Anniversary Celebration, May 25, 1916 (Box-folder 2-36)
- McConnell Auditorium, 1949 (Box-folder 2-37)
- New Science Building, 1965 (Box-folder 2-38)
- Aerial Photograph Central Washington State College, 1966 (Box-folder 2-39)
- Aerial Photograph Central Washington State College, 1966 (Box-folder 2-40)
- Old Library (Barge Hall), 1920s (Box-folder 2-41)